这是我的朋友，杰里和玛姬·赛尔比。
These are my friends, Jerry and Marge Selbee.
他们住在密歇根的埃沃特。
They live in Evart, Michigan.
这是一个并非全盛时期的小镇。
It's a small town that's not exactly in its prime.
不过说实话，杰瑞和马姬也不是。
Though, to be honest, neither are Jerry and Marge.
今天，他们正在去买彩票的路上。
Today, they're on their way to buy lottery tickets.
很多很多的彩票。
Lots and lots of lottery tickets.
但他们不希望自己走运。
But they're not hoping to get lucky.
你看，他们不需要运气。
You see, they don't need luck.
但故事并不是从这里开始的。
But this story doesn't start there.
故事从杰里开始，42年来，他每天都在黎明前起床，去玉米片厂工作，因为他担心这将是他最后一次上班。
It starts with Jerry, getting up before dawn just like he has every day for 42 years, going to work at the Corn Flakes factory, for what he fears will be the last time.
这其实是个数学问题。
It's a math problem, really.
如果你数一数，除了"I "这个字母，因为它看起来像"1"所以省略了，你就会发现"J"是二月。
If you count the letters, uh, except the letter "I," which they skip because it looks like a "1", then you realize that "J" is February.
然后，最后一个字母……哦,男孩。
And then, the last letter... Oh, boy.
这就指定了植物代码，不容易弄清楚，但是，呃…我做到了。
That designates the plant code, which was not easy to figure out, but, uh... I did.
杰瑞，你没必要这么努力工作。你退休。
Jerry, you don't have to work so hard. You're retiring.
嗯,是的。但是…我…我不需要这样。嗯…我知道我的电话挂断了，但是…你知道的，我对数字有一种情结。
Well, yeah. But... I... I don't have to be. Um... I know my line is shutting down, but... You know, I have a thing with numbers.
来吧。
Come on.
你已经服完刑了。这是你的黄金岁月。
You've served your time. These are your golden years.
他是我们最好的部门经理，对吧?
He's the best line manager we ever had, right?
绝对的。
Absolutely.
嘿。不如你告诉他们你是怎么从高中开始在这里工作的?
Hey. Why don't you tell these guys how you started working here in high school?
你上夜班，对吧?
You worked nights, right?
杰里。——好的。
To Jerry.- All right.
不是每个人都能坚持42年不被解雇的。
Not everybody can pull off 42 years without getting fired.
现在你的老板会让你睡个懒觉。
And now you have a boss who's going to let you sleep in.
也不会对我大吼大叫。
And won't yell at me.
这么错了。
Wrong about that.Oh.
你应该去考房地产执照，就像霍华德那样。
You know, you should get your real estate license, just like Howard did.
这就像有一份工作。
It's like having a job.
但这也像退休一样，因为你什么都不用做。
But it's also like being retired, because you don't do anything.
这是真的。
It's true.
大多数时候，我都不出家门。
Most days, I don't even leave the house.
嗯…你知道，我会成功的。
Well... You know, I'll make it work.
你知道，我总能帮马姬做家务。
You know, I can always help Marge around the house.
不，你不需要这么做。
No, you don't need to do that.
不，我很乐意。
No, I'd be happy to.
我是说，你照顾这个地方这么多年了。
I mean, you've been taking care of this place for years.
我有一个系统。
I kind of have a system.
是啊，而且还不错。
Oh, yeah, and a good one.
但是，你知道，每个系统都可以改进。
But, you know, every system can use an improvement.
哦,上帝。我们开始吧。
Oh, God. Here we go.
嘿。我有个主意。是吗?
Hey. I got an idea. Yeah?
为什么不让我去你们的一些工作网站做咨询呢?
Why don't I try consulting on some of your job sites?
你知道的，想办法让事情变得更好。
You know, find ways of making things run better.Ah.
你想在我的工地走来走去告诉我哪里做错了吗?现钞。
You wanna walk around on my construction site and tell me what I'm doing wrong? Oof.
我不会要价太高的。
I wouldn't charge much.
我还得付钱给你吗?
Oh, and I have to pay you for this?
该死的正确的。-你也会过来教我妻子如何批改论文吗?
Darn right.- Are you going to also come by and teach my wife how to grade papers?
嘿，爸爸，如果我住在这里，我会很高兴的。
Hey, Dad, if I lived here, I would welcome that.
谢谢你,黎明。
Thank you, Dawn.
我要接受你的建议。
I'm gonna take you up on that.
我以后要经常开车去大急流城。
I'm gonna drive down to Grand Rapids more often.
哦,哎呀。
Oh, whoops.
你卖得太好了。
You sold it too well.
闭嘴。结果却适得其反。
Shut up. Backfired right in your face.
是的,亲爱的?好吧。
Yeah, sweetie? Okay.
我们能给爷爷看吗?
Can we show Pop Pop?
你想现在就给爷爷看吗?
Uh, yeah, you wanna show Pop Pop right now?
给我看什么?
Show me what?
我们给你准备了退休礼物。——惊喜。
We got you a retirement present.- Surprise.
好吧。
Okay.
睁开你的眼睛。——开放。
Open your eyes.- Open.
不会吧!
Holy cow!
一艘渔船。什么……我喜欢钓鱼吗?我该怎么办?好吧。是的，你带过我一次。
A fishing boat. What... Do I like fishing? I do? Okay. Yeah, you took me once.
现在你想什么时候走都可以了。
Yeah, now you can go whenever you want.
是啊，怎么样?
Yeah, how about that?
这是伟大的。谢谢你！
This is great. Thank you.
谢谢，谢谢，谢谢。-哦,好的。
Thank you, thank you, thank you.- Oh, good.
哦。-爸爸喜欢。
Oh.- Dad likes it.
还有你，保守秘密。
And you, for keeping a secret.
谢谢你,南瓜。
Thank you, pumpkin.
谢谢你,道格。你喜欢它吗?
Thank you, Doug. You like it?
是的。——好的。
Yeah.- All right.
我的天啊。
My goodness.
我的天啊。——好。你没有破坏它。
My goodness.- Good job. You didn't spoil it.
那是你唯一的工作。你做得很好。你没事吧?
That was your one job. You did so good. You okay?
哦,是的。是的。
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
我没有很多普通的衣服。
I don't have many regular clothes.
都是工作服。
It's all work shirts.
我们可以给你买更多衣服。
Well, we can get you more clothes.
嗯。
Hmm.
这需要调整。
It'll be an adjustment.
你会找到路的。
You'll find your way.
嗯。
Hmm.
有你吗?
Have you?
不是真的。但是我没有船。
Not really. But I don't have a boat.
你想要这个吗?
You want this one?
不。
Nope.
早上,莱昂。早上好,杰里。
Morning, Leon. Morning, Jerry.
卡被拒绝了，海伦。我很抱歉。
Card was declined, Helen. I'm sorry.
讨厌它。也许我有现金。让我……
Dang it. Maybe I have cash. Let me just...
我知道你有这个能力。
I know you're good for it.
谢谢你,莱昂。
Thanks, Leon.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing out here?
我的约会是在9点。
My appointment is at-00.
不，你说你10点来。
No, you said you'd come at-00.
我没有其他预约。我有六个客户。
I don't have any other appointments. I have six clients.
好吧。
Okay.
只有六个客户，你怎么谋生?
How do you make a living with only six clients?
我不喜欢。我刚成为一个在线旅行社。看到海报了吗?
I don't. I just became an online travel agent. See the posters?
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
既然都在网上了，为什么还需要海报呢?
So, why do you need posters if it's online?
因为它们是免费的。
Because they were free.
为什么你总是要理解所有事情背后的原因?
Why do you always have to understand the reasoning behind everything?
哦,好吧。
Oh, well.
只有这样我才能理清头绪。
It's the only way I can make sense of things.
船怎么样了?
How's the boat?
水还是太冷了。
Water's still too cold.
你不下水。这就是这艘船的意义所在。
You don't get in the water. That's the point of the boat.
嗯。我的账户是怎么回事?
Hmm. How's my account?
说到冷……
Speaking of cold...
2%的涨幅，听起来不算多，因为事实并非如此。
2% gains, which doesn't sound like much, because it isn't.
听着，你得更有攻击性。
Look, you gotta be more aggressive.
如果你让我投资股票，我可能会给你10%的收益。
If you let me put that in stocks, I could probably get you 10%.
这只会让你的钱翻倍…7.27年。
That would double your money in only... 7.27 years.
这是我今天唯一一次可以用它。
Literally the only time I was going to get to use that today.
不。
Nope.
这是我们的全部。
This is all we've got.
我可不想拿它来赌博。
And I'm not about to gamble with it.
这不是赌博。这似乎有风险，但市场……是啊，如果你输了，那就是赌博。
It's not gambling. It seems like a risk, but the market... Yeah, well, if you could lose it, it's gambling.
我一个月后再打电话给你预约。
I'll call you in a month for my next appointment.
不需要预约，好的。
Don't need an appointment.Okay.
把船开出去。
Take out the boat.
我可能会这么做。
I may just do that.
哦!
Oh!
不。
No.
不会吧!
Holy cow!
嘿,悲观主义者
Hey, Jer.
什么是roll down?-就是头奖达到200万，但没人得到6个数字。
What's a roll down?- It's when the jackpot hits two million and nobody gets six numbers.
然后整个头奖就会落在得到三四个的人身上…无论什么。
Then the whole jackpot rolls down to the people who got three or four... Whatever.
更好的机会。
Just better odds.
祝你好运。Yeah.Thanks。
Good luck. Yeah.Thanks.
更好的机会。
Better odds.
这是对的吗?
Can that be right?
好吧。
All right.
这不是赌博。
It's not gambling.
彩票吗?是的。每次都有赢的方法。
The lottery? Yup. There's a way to win every time.
你中风了吗?
Are you having a stroke?
有一个他们没有发现的漏洞，它就在数学中。
There's a loophole they didn't see, and it's right here in the math.
现在，在一次典型的抽奖中，你有54分之一的机会中6个数字中的3个，和1500分之一的机会中4个。
Now, on a typical drawing, you'd have a one in 54 chance of hitting three out of six numbers, and a one in 1,500 chance of hitting four.
很有可能你每次都输。
Odds are you'll lose every time.
不是每一次。
Not every time.
我上周赢了一张免费的票，结果输了。
I won a free ticket last week, which lost.
但在下一周，较低数字的奖金会高于你愿意支付的金额。
But on the roll down weeks, the payouts to the lower numbers increases above the amount that you would pay to play.
所以，数学对你有利。
So, the math is in your favor.
他们错过了。
And they missed it.
我不知道这是什么意思。
I don't know what this says.
看起来像是一个疯子在牢房墙上画的数字。
Looks like the numbers a crazy man drew on his cell wall.
这意味着在接下来的几周，你肯定会赢。
It means that on the roll down weeks, you're guaranteed to win.
这不可能是真的。
That can't be true.
为什么不呢?因为这是彩票，杰瑞。
Why not? Because it's the lottery, Jerry.
在底特律有一群人，他们的工作就是知道数字是如何工作的。他们做的事。
There's a building of people in Detroit whose job it is to know how the numbers work. And they do.
真不敢相信你是我的会计。
I cannot believe you are my accountant.
兼职会计。
Part-time accountant.
全职在线旅行社。
Full-time online travel agent.
嘿,明迪。
Hey, Mindy.
嘿,杰瑞。存款?
Hey, Jerry. Making a deposit?
哦,不…我…我想取2000美元。
Uh, no... I... I'd like to withdraw $2,000.
是的。
Yep.
你的脚怎么样了?
So, how are your feet?
是更好的。
Been better.
滚动网球有帮助，直到我的经理被它绊了一下，把它扔到了街上。
Rolling the tennis ball helped, until my manager tripped on it and threw it into the street.
我可以再给您拿一份来。
I can bring you another one.
它们是三个一组的。
They come in threes.Thanks.
噢,谢谢你。
Oh, thank you.
我过几天会带着押金回来。
I'll be back in a couple of days with a deposit.
好吧。
Okay.
哦。
Oh.
可能比这个多20%
Probably be 20% more than this.
给予或获得。
Give or take.
then.Okay见到你。
See you then.Okay.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
好吧。祝你今天愉快。
Okay. Have a good day.
两千张WinFall门票。
Two thousand WinFall tickets.
二千年?
Two thousand?
是的,女士。
Yes, ma'am.
大家晚上好，欢迎参加本周的WinFall抽奖活动。
Good evening, folks, and welcome to this week's WinFall lottery roll down.
拿好你们的票，坐下来，我们直接开始吧。
Grab your tickets, have a seat and let's get right to it.
第一个幸运数字是6。
The first lucky number is six.
第二个数字…
The second number...
23。
Twenty-three.
你没事吧?哦,是的。没有更好的。
You okay? Oh, yeah. Never better.
43。那艘船怎么样了?
Forty-three. So, how'd it go with the boat?
哦,嗯…他们说他们能修好马达，但不是给我的。
Oh, uh... They said they can fix the motor, but it's not for me.
我是说，我们本来就应该一起做事的，对吧?
I mean, we're supposed to be doing stuff together anyway, right?
31。
Thirty-one.
你想看电影吗?-下一个中奖号码是…哦……不，我不是说现在- 10。
You want to watch a movie?- The next winning number is... Oh... No, I didn't mean right now.- Ten.
所以,什么时候?嗯，我不知道。
Well, so, when? Well, I don't know.
我在看一个节目。
I'm watching a program.
你看这个吗?
You're watching this?
不。
No.
43 31 10 32。
Forty-three, 31, 10, and 32.
我们希望你是赢家。
And we hope you're a winner.
一个……
One...
这是一个四。
That's one's four.
21、28。
Twenty-one, 28.
十六岁。
Sixteen.
问题是，没人知道这个小镇。
Problem is, nobody knows about this town.
埃沃特应该开始以一美元的价格出售房子，就像托斯卡纳那样。
Evart should start selling houses for a dollar, like they do in Tuscany.
吸引人。
Lure people here.
一美元就能住在托斯卡纳?
We can live in Tuscany for a dollar?
一欧元。
Well, a Euro.
这是一个美元。
That's a dollar.
不，比那个多一点。
No, a little more than that.
杰瑞，一欧元多少钱?
Jerry, how much is a Euro?
杰里。
Jerry.
哦。
Oh.
对不起。
Sorry.
嗯。
Mmm.
浪漫满屋。
Full house.
我们在玩杜松子酒。
We're playing gin.
哦。
Oh.
非常感谢。——好的。好吧,晚安。
Thank you so much.- All right. Well, goodnight.
晚安。——照顾。
Goodnight.- Take care.
祝你回家走得愉快。——好的。
Have a good walk home.- Okay.
金酒、扑克、克里比奇，我都搞不懂。-你才不在乎你不在乎。
Gin, or poker, or cribbage, I get confused by them all. - You don't care. You don't care.
拼字游戏。Scrabblenext。
Scrabble. Scrabblenext.
好吧,晚上。
All right, night.
你得告诉我发生了什么事。
You're going to have to tell me what's going on.
我太老了，等不及了。
I'm too old to wait it out.
哦……我错过了机会。
Oh... I missed my chance.
我做了我该做的一切。
I did everything I was supposed to do.
我必须做的一切。
Everything I had to do.
现在再做别的都太晚了。
Now it's too late to do anything else.
哦，你的生活还没有结束。
Oh, your life isn't over.
每个人似乎都这么认为。
Everybody seems to think it is.
嗯…
Well...
见鬼，我什么都能做。
Heck, I can do anything.
如果他们不切断我的生产线，我现在还在工厂。
I'd still be at the factory if they didn't cut my line.
而是……这是我的黄金岁月。
But instead... These are my golden years.
是啊，事情没有按照你想要的方式发展，不代表它不会。
Yeah, just because things didn't work out the way you wanted, doesn't mean they won't.
好运和坏都有。
Good luck happens, same as bad.
什么?
What?
祝你好运，和坏运气一样吗?
Good luck, it happens same as bad?
是的。它只是math.Yeah。
Yeah. It's just math.Yeah.
什么?哦,男人。什么是假。
What? Oh, man. What a dummy.
不是你。我。
Not you. Me.
你是一个天才。
You're a genius.
样本大小。
Sample size.
这就是我的错误所在。
That is where I went wrong.
我没有计算概率的频率。
I didn't calculate the frequency of probability.
这只是数学。
It's just math.
哦，我不喜欢数学。
Oh, I don't like math.
哦。哦,我很抱歉。
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry.
来，我给你看看……在这里。所以，如果你把一枚硬币抛1000次，你仍然可能得到60%的正面。
Here, let me show you... Here. So, if you take a coin and you flipped it 1,000 times, you might still get 60% heads.
但如果你投掷5000次，概率会接近50%
But if you flipped it 5,000 times, the probability gets closer to 50%.
样本必须足够大，才能把运气排除在外。
The sample has to be large enough to take luck out of the equation.
这是给你的。
And this is for you.
你存一分钱吗?
Are you depositing a penny?
不。不。
No. No.
不。嗯…我想取钱。
No. Uh... I wanna make a withdrawal.
4200美元。
$4,200.
那我们还剩多少钱?
Oh, and how much does that leave us with?
我检查。
I am checking.
4点多一点。
A little over four.
好吧。
Okay.
那就6个吧。
Make it six, then.
六个?嗯。
Six? Mmm-hmm.
八?
Eight?
八? 8000美元。
Eight?$8,000.
你确定吗?嗯。
Are you sure? Hmm.
九十八年。
Ninety-eight.
九十九年。
Ninety-nine.
八千年。
Eight thousand.
谢谢你,蚊。
Thank you, Midge.
好了。
There we go.
再见。
Bye-bye.
每个小镇都有自己的特色。
You know, every town has a thing.
我们需要一个东西。
We need a thing.
爵士音乐节怎么了?
What happened to jazz fest?
我们没法让舞台保持正常。
Well, we couldn't keep the stage up to code.
有个穿木屐的女孩正好掉进去了。
Oh, one of those clogger girls fell right through.
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
爵士音乐节也赚了钱。
Jazz fest made money, too.
我是说，不是那一年，因为那女孩起诉了我们。
I mean, not that year, because the girl sued us.Yeah.
她很生气，因为我们还在鼓掌。
She was upset 'cause we were still clapping.
我们以为这是表演的一部分。
We thought it was part of the show.
哦。
Oh.
对了，我们几个人今晚要集资买彩票。
By the way, a bunch of us are pooling money for the lottery tonight.
他们在做滚下的事情，你可以赢得更多。
They're doing that roll down thing, where you can win more.
我们不是买彩票的人。-这样最好不过了
We're not lottery people.- That's probably for the best.
你知道吗，有些人会在这些东西上花上千美元?
You know, there are some people who blow thousands on those things?
你对吧?-开始了。
You all right?- Here we go.
有什么事吗?喝。-下错管道了。
What's the matter? Take the drink.- Down the wrong pipe.
吃得太快了。
Eating too fast.
是的。
Yeah.
哦。
Ooh.
四。
Four.
喔!
Whoo.
我是说，就像普通的旅行社，但它是在线的，所以当事情不顺利时，人们可以表现得像动物一样。
I mean, it's like a regular travel agent, but it's online, so people can act like animals when something doesn't work out.
嘿，你应该去旅行。
Hey, you should be traveling.
你和温迪以前经常坐游轮回来，什么都叫左舷和右舷。
You and Wendy used to go on all these cruises and come back and call everything port and starboard.
我都不知道哪个是哪个。
I didn't even know which was which.
这取决于你在哪个海洋上。
Depends which ocean you're on.
嗯。不。不。——是的。
Hmm. No. No.- Yep.
她会希望你开心的。
She'd want you to have fun.
已经三年了。
It's been three years.
哦,小鬼。小鬼和汉堡。所有的吗?
Oh, brats. Brats and burgers. All?
上面有奶酪。好的。
With cheese on it.Okay.
小鬼和…哦。——切达干酪?
Brats and... Oh.- Cheddar?
道格，你能帮我看一下烤架吗?
Doug, would you watch the grill for a second?
看到了吗?这是个好时机。嗯?
See? This is a good time. Huh?
嗯。我跟你说了，开车去是值得的。
Mmm. I told you it'd be worth the drive.
不，你说你不知道还剩多少个周末。
No, you said you didn't know how many weekends you have left.
好吧,我不喜欢。
Well, I don't.
是的，但是数学是有用的。
Yeah, but the math works.
开两小时车，就能得到免费汉堡。
Drive for two hours, get a free burger.
抵消了汽油的成本。
Offsets the cost of gas.
我不吃肉，爸爸。
I don't eat meat, Dad.
哦,对了。我去买鸡肉。
Oh, right. I'll get the chicken.
不，那还是肉。
No, that's still meat.
好吧。
Okay.
他是好的吗?
Is he okay?
他只是不知道怎么表达"我想你"
He just doesn't know the formula for "I miss you."
有你在的时候会更有趣。
It is more fun when you're here.
我知道，但你和爸爸，你们在一起会很开心的。
I know, but you and Dad, you gotta have fun together.
是的。
Yeah.
我知道你等他退休等了很久。我知道。
I know you've waited a really long time for him to retire. I know.
我知道。我们需要努力。
I know. We need to work on it.
我都不记得我们上次是什么时候…你知道吗?什么?
I can't even remember the last time that we had... You know? What?
是的。哦，不，没关系。我不需要听你说……蜂蜜。
Yeah. Oh, no, that's okay. I don't need to hear about... Honey.
我要去喝杯啤酒。
I'm gonna get a beer.
好吧?好吧。我们会解决的。
Okay? Okay. We'll work on it.
反正我也在考虑。——好的。
I'm thinking about it anyway.- Okay.
我希望他会。
I wish he would.
哇。
Whoa.
哇,哇,哇!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
不，丽萃，丽萃，丽萃!不不不，莉兹。
No, Lizzy, Lizzy, Lizzy! No, no, no, no, Liz.
我们不要……我们不要打开它。
Let's not... Let's not open that.
为什么?我想要爆米花。我知道。我知道。
Why? I want the popcorn. I know. I know.
但这…这爆米花太不新鲜了。啊。
But this... this popcorn's very stale. Ugh.
我喜欢陈旧。
I like stale.
但这里面全是糖。这对你没有好处。
Well, but this is full of sugar. It's no good for you.
我看见你吃了七块奥利奥。
I saw you eat seven Oreos.
你想吃奥利奥吗?
You want an Oreo?
你都吃了，爷爷。
You ate them all, Pop Pop.
好吧。好吧。嗯…等我一分钟。
Okay. All right. Uh... Let me just have it for one minute.
爷爷会还给你的。我保证。
Pop Pop will give it back to you. I promise.
你现在相信爷爷了，对吧?
You trust Pop Pop now, right?
让我花一分钟。
Let me just take one minute.
我马上就出去。
And I'll be right out.
给你。
Here you go.
接受。谢谢,流行流行。
Take. Thanks, Pop Pop.
是的。
Yep.
有什么想告诉我的吗?
Something you wanna tell me?
什么?
What?
储藏室。
The pantry.
我在买彩票。
I'm playing the lottery.
我是说那袋空的奥利奥。
I meant the empty bag of Oreos.
我在玩彩票，而且我要赢了。
I'm playing the lottery, and I'm winning.
我算了一下，赢了一万五千美元。
I figured out the math, and I won $15,000.
它被塞在磨砂迷你小麦盒子里。
It's stuffed inside the Frosted Mini-Wheats box.
哇。
Wow.
我给雪莉的彩票池捐了20美元。
I gave $20 to Shirley's lottery pool.
我想现在没什么大不了的了。
I guess it's not such a big deal now.
我…我必须试一试。
I... I had to try it.
我…我在游戏中发现了这个缺陷，我必须弄清楚我的判断是否正确。
I... I found this flaw in the game, and I had to find out if I was right.
那你为什么不直接告诉我?
Well, why didn't you just tell me?
我…觉得自己很愚蠢。
I... felt silly.
我们几乎没有足够的钱退休，而且……现在不是冒险的时候。
We barely have enough money to retire on as it is, and... This is no time to risk it.
是的,它是。什么?
Yes, it is. What?
是时候冒险了。
It's time to risk it.
因为现在我们失去了更重要的东西。
Because right now we're losing something that matters even more.
我已经等了四十年，希望只有我们两个人，但到目前为止，我们做得很糟糕。
I've waited 40 years for it to be just us, and so far we kind of suck at it.
我们有危险。
We have Jeopardy.
哦，这不是问题。杰里!
Oh, that's not a thing. Jerry!
我想玩得开心。
I wanna have fun.
我们做点蠢事吧。嗯?
Let's be a little stupid. Huh?
我们17岁就结婚了，所以我们知道该怎么做。
We got married when we were 17, so we know how to do it.
嗯,这是真的。
Well, that's true.
我们需要一些东西。
We need something for us.
我没想到会是买彩票，但如果能让我们聊点什么，我也会去抢银行。
I didn't think it would be playing the lottery, but I'd rob a bank if it gave us something to talk about.
好吧。
Okay.
15000美元?是的。
$15,000?Yep.
如果我们把一万五千美元全押上…哦,我们应该。我们全押上吧。你认为呢?
If we bet the whole $15,000... Oh, we should. Let's bet it all. You think?
是啊，因为我也这么想。它是正确的…不。不，不，不。
Yeah, 'cause I was thinking the same thing. It's right... No. No, no, no, no.
里昂，WinFall怎么了?
Leon, what happened to WinFall?
哦,他们……他们逐步淘汰了它。
Oh, they... they phased it out.
什么?它就这样消失了?
What? It's gone, just like that?
反正你也不玩，对吧?
You don't play anyway, do you?
不。好吧，我想现在人们只能在马萨诸塞州玩了。
No.Yeah, well, I guess people will just have to play the one in Massachusetts now.
数学工作。你可以看到。你是一个会计。
The math works. You can see that. You're an accountant.
是的。我的意思是……我是说，看起来是对的。
Yeah. I mean... I mean, it looks right.
马萨诸塞州也不远。
And Massachusetts isn't that far.
不，如果我们的卡车不抛锚的话，大概只有10个小时的车程。
No, it's only about a 10-hour drive if our truck doesn't break down.
如果有，我们就搭个车。
If it does, we'll get a ride.Yeah.
从谁?
From whom?
卡车司机。是的，他们总是在寻找同伴。
Truckers. Yeah, they're always looking for company.
谋杀。如果情况变得奇怪，我们就跳出去。
To murder. We'll jump out if it gets weird.
他们甚至不会知道我们有一大包现金。
And they won't even know that we have a duffle bag full of cash.
是的，我们会把拉链拉上的。
Yeah, we'll keep that zipped up.
好吧。好吧,什么?
All right. All right, what?
我也在。
I'm in, too.
你确定吗?——没有。
You sure?- No.
但管他呢?给我投1000。
But what the hell? Put me in for 1,000.
我刚要取消一个游轮旅行。
I just got a cruise I gotta cancel now.
嘿。Oh.Oh。我们的晚餐。
Hey. Oh.Oh. Got our dinner.
是的。我们需要三天的食物。
Yeah. We're going to need three days of food.
哦。
Oh.
我给我们找了个小镇玩。
And I found us a small town to play in.
是的，保持安静。
Yeah, keep things quiet.
就像我把车停在一个街区外的旧货市场。
You know, like how I park a block away at a good garage sale.
是吗?Oh.Move。
Yeah? Oh.Move.
你有业余无线电吗?什么?
You got a ham radio? What?
业余无线电。我们要去一些死亡区。
Ham radio. We're gonna hit some dead zones.
我想我可以去Ace…等一下。
I suppose I can go to Ace... Wait a minute.
电池怎么样了?
How are we on batteries?
嗯…我…啊。
Uh... I... Ah.
好吧。我们再去买一些吧。以防。
Okay. Let's get some more. Just in case.
感觉我们真的是在抢银行。
Feels like we really are robbing a bank.
不。会更有趣的。你把。
Nah. It's gonna be more fun. You take that.
给你钥匙。
Here are the keys.
好吧。啊。
All right. Aah.
我有优惠券。
I got the coupons.
好吧。你抓住。
All right. You grab that.
哦,现在呢?哦。
Oh, now? Oh.
让我们go.Oh。
Let's go.Oh.
我可以先穿衣服吗?
Can I get dressed first?
Mmm.Whoo。
Mmm.Whoo.
你有饼干吗?
You have cookies?
哦。
Ooh.
看起来不太像。
Doesn't look like much.
我们只需要一台售票机，对吧?
Well, all we need is a ticket machine, right?
嘿，孩子，这些是买一送一的，因为它们太过时了。
Hey, kid, those are buy one, get one free, 'cause they're so out of date.
这是2013年的，但还是会让你的嘴变蓝。
They're from 2013, but they'll still turn your mouth blue.
事实上，我要先去拿。
Actually, I'm gonna get them first.
我能为您做些什么?
How can I help you?
我们想买八千张《WinFall》的门票。
We'd like to buy 8,000 WinFall tickets.
我先去找你。
I'm gonna get you first.
这远远不够。
No way is this enough.
这绝对不够。
There's no way that was enough.
嗯…八千张《WinFall》门票…29000美元。
Uh... Eight thousand WinFall tickets is, like... $29,000.
16000。16000美元。
No. 16,000.$16,000.
这就是我们带来的。
And that is how much we brought.
机器每小时打印1000张票，所以你要在这里待一整天。
Well, the machine prints 1,000 tickets an hour, so you'll be here all day.
根据我的经验，在这里待一天太糟糕了。
And let me tell you from experience, being here all day sucks.
因为我一整天都在这里。
Because I'm here all day.
嗯,他是对的。需要8个小时。
Well, he's right. It's gonna take eight hours.
我能做到。滚吧。
I can do it. Let's get rolling.
你想我们吗?是的,来吧。我还有工作要做。
You want us? Yeah, come on. I got work to do.
我很忙。你能给我们演示一下吗?
I'm busy. Well, can you show us how it works?
你会想出办法的。
You'll figure it out.
对不起，旅馆不太好。
Sorry, the motel's not so great.
镐和铲子。
The Pick and Shovel.
完美的名字。
Perfect name.
因为这是你挖坟墓所需要的。
Because it's what you need to dig a grave.
哈。让我想起了我们的新婚之夜。
Hah. Reminds me of our wedding night.
嗯?
Huh?
我爸给了我足够的钱让我带你去舞会。
My dad gave me enough money to take you to the prom.
但我又想"见鬼，舞会午夜就结束了"但婚姻，却能天长地久。
But then I thought, "Heck, the prom ends at midnight, "but a marriage, that lasts forever.
“而且还便宜20美元。”
"And it's 20 bucks cheaper."
你是在戴斯酒店度过的。
Which you spent on a Days Inn.
哦，在我们度蜜月的时候。
Oh, on our honeymoon.Yeah.
我很高兴我们都疯了。
Well, I'm glad we're being crazy.
如果有必要，我会睡在车里。
I'd sleep in the car if I had to.
好吧，你可能不得不这么做。
Well, you may have to.
我想这门锁不上。
I don't think this door locks.
噢，开始了，杰瑞。哦，哦，哦，哦。
Oh, it's on, Jerry. Oh, oh, oh, oh.
好吧。
All right.
哦，你有…交叉手指，我们最后一个幸运数字是21。
Oh, you have the... Cross those fingers, our very last lucky number is 21.
各位，这些数字，再来一次，是23 45 01 25 06和21。
Folks, those numbers, one more time, are 23, 45, 01, 25, 06 and 21.
好了，伙计们，检查一下这些数字。我们祝你好运。
All right, folks, check those numbers. We wish you the best of luck.
希望这是你的一周。
Hopefully this was your week.Okay.
我们有八千张票要查。
Well, we got 8,000 tickets to check.
让我们开始吧。
Let's get started.
我们可能会看到日出。
We'll probably see sunrise.
最后一个是三位数的冠军。
The last one is a three-number winner.
哦,很好。
Oh, good.
好吧。
Okay.
所以我们押了16000。
So we bet 16,000.Mmm-hmm.
两个号码的中奖者会给我们免费的门票，所以如果我们把他们算作推动…这意味着我们…21043美元。
And the two number winners just gives us free tickets, so if we count those as a push... Which means we made... $21,043.
哦……我觉得我们需要更多奥利奥。
Oh... I think we're gonna need more Oreos.
是的,我们都…不,真见鬼。还留了一小块给你。
Yeah, we're all... No, heck. There's a little piece left there for you.
不。你确定你不……不了,谢谢。
No.You sure you don't... No, thank you.
他们只是说:“恭喜你。”嗯。
They just said, "Congratulations." Huh.
当然了。
Of course they did.
买票不违反规定。
It's not against the rules to buy tickets.
我以为警报会响，他们就会对我大吼大叫。
I thought an alarm would go off and they'd start yelling at me.
我也是。
So did I.
你真以为只有我们知道吗?
Do you really think we're the only ones who know?
为什么我们的厕所隔间上有超声波传感器?
Hey, why are there ultrasonic sensors on our toilet stalls?
浴室空置网格。
Bathroom vacancy grid.
我厌倦了走在那里看到每个隔间下都有脚。
I got tired of walking in there and seeing feet under every stall.
所以，现在我知道当灯是绿色的时候，厕所是……不干净，但没人坐在上面。
So, now I know that when the light is green, the toilet is... Well, not clean, but nobody is sitting on it.
我们应该在做研究项目。
We're supposed to be doing our research projects.
我是。
I am.
浴室灯吗?不。那是愚蠢的。
Bathroom lights? No. That'd be stupid.
我正在做一个关于彩票的。
I'm doing one on the lottery.
啊。那就蠢多了。
Ah. That's way more stupid.
它不是。我在评估强力球和超级百万的确切胜率。
It's not. I'm evaluating the exact odds of winning Power ball versus Mega Millions.
好吧。是的,它是愚蠢的。无论什么。我还是会得到B。
Okay. Yeah, it's stupid. Whatever. I'll still get a B.
这些是什么?
What are these?
较小的州运动会。我需要它们作比较。
The smaller state games. I need them for comparison.
甜的。残疾人专用隔间开着。
Sweet. The handicapped stall is open.
杰瑞,靠边停车。
Jerry, pull over.
快点，靠边停车。我们离家只有一英里了。
Come on, pull over. We're only a mile from home.
不。你hold不住?
No.You can't hold it?
这并不是说。
It's not that.
好吧。好吧。
Okay. Okay.
马姬，这要花多长时间?
Marge, how long is this gonna take?
因为我真的得走了
'Cause I actually have to go.
你有没有想过也许世界并没有与你擦肩而过?
Did you ever think maybe the world wasn't passing you by?
也许你注定会在这里。
Maybe you were meant to be here.
在工厂里工作，像你一样关心这些人，因为总有一天你可以帮助他们。
To work in the factory and to care about all these people the way you do, because the day would come when you could help them.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
你说我们赌得越多，胜算就越大。
Well, you said the more we bet, the better the odds.
我确实说过。
I did say that.
你想成立一家公司?
So you wanna start a corporation?
把全城的人都招来。
Bring in the whole town.
如果我们卖掉股份，我们就有更多的资本来投资。
If we sell shares, we'll have more capital to invest.
要么做大，要么回家。
Go big or go home.
那我们就和股东们分享利润。
Then we'll split the profits with the shareholders.
每个人都骑。
Everybody rides.
你能不能别那样说话?
Will you stop talking like that?
对不起。我真的很喜欢。
Sorry. I'm just really into it.
她真的很喜欢。
She's really into it.
因为她知道这行得通。
Because she knows it'll work.
房子总是赢家。
House always wins.
阻止它。
Stop it.
你真的认为人们会参与进来吗?
You really think people will come in on this?
是的。你所做的。
Yup. You did.
是啊，但我是个绝望的鳏夫，没有任何生活目标。
Yeah, but I'm a depressed widower with nothing to live for.
那你想买更多的股票?是的!
You wanna buy more shares, then? Yes!
就是这样。
And that about does it.
有什么问题吗?
Any questions?
那么，GS投资策略公司?这是正确的。
So, uh, GS Investment Strategies? That's right.
我们有营业执照，什么都有。
We've got a business license and everything.
不是个好名字。
Not much of a name.
好吧，不用担心名字。
Well, don't worry about the name.
你需要在某个地方加上“彩票”。
You need "lottery" in there somewhere.
名字不重要。
Well, the name's not important.
如果你想推销你的想法，那就是。我上了一门市场营销的课。
It is if you wanna sell the idea. I took a class on marketing.
好吧，这个想法很畅销。你以500美元的价格买一股股票，然后获利。
Well, the idea sells itself. You buy a share for $500 and you make a profit.
就是这么简单。你有商标吗?
It's that simple. Do you have a logo?
不需要logo。商标的帮助。
Don't need a logo. Logos help.
我有一头猪在拖拉机上。
I have a pig on a tractor.
是的。好吧，听着，你们都认识我很多年了。
Yeah. Okay, look, you all have known me for years.
这招会管用的，对大家都有帮助。
This will work, and it'll help everybody.
如果我们想加入，但我们拖欠了账单，没钱分一杯羹怎么办?
What if we want in, but we're behind on our bills, and don't have enough for a share?
你们接受其他付款方式吗?
Do you accept other forms of payment?
像什么?
Like what?
等等,等等,等等。
Wait, wait, wait.
都在这里。
Got it all right here.
哦,我们在。
Oh, we're in.
我从没做过这种犯罪的事。
I've never done anything criminal like this.
不，雪莉，这不是犯罪
No, Shirley, it's not criminal.
我们要为所有赢来的钱缴税，报销所有费用。
We're gonna pay taxes on all the winnings and claim expenses.
杰瑞把一切都安排好了。
Jerry's got it all worked out.
你妈妈和我要去做生意了。
Your mother and I are going into business.
你是在卖太妃糖什么的吗?
Are you selling her toffee or something?
不。我们要去买彩票。
No. We're gonna play the lottery.
500美元一份，好的。
It's 500 a share.Okay.
噢,是吗?好吧?你不想知道细节吗?
Oh, yeah? Okay? You don't wanna know details?
不不不，我很好。听起来很不错。
No, no, no, I'm good. It sounds great.
你可以在前三部《爸爸，爸爸》中看到。
You can see in the first three plays Dad, Dad.
我们增加了利润。
That we've increased our profit.
它不适合我。
It's just not for me.
我就是不明白。这只是数学。
I just don't understand this. It's just math.
总是数学问题。
It's always just math.
这就像在硬币中分类，寻找水牛硬币，因为你已经计算过了，每七个卷中就有一个?
It's like sorting through coins, looking for buffalo nickels, because you had calculated there was, what, one in every seven rolls or something?
是的。我们赚了600美元。
Yeah. We made $600.
整整一个月，我们每个周末都在整理硬币。我12岁的时候。
We sorted through coins every weekend for a month. I was 12.
它是乐趣。
It was fun.
要是能扔个足球什么的就好了。
It would have been nice to just throw the football or something.
看,我…嘿,道格?
Look, I'm... Hey, Doug?
道格，波特家的谷仓停电了他们想让你去看看。
Doug, the Porters lost power in their barn and they want you to come take a look.
好吧。我马上就来。
All right. I'll be right there.
好吧。我要go.Okay。是的。
Okay. I gotta go.Okay. Yup.
我会帮你的，爷爷。
I'll be in your business, Pop Pop.
你对商标印象如何?好。
How are you at logos? Good.
好吧，过来给爷爷看。
Well, come here and show Pop Pop.
在这里。
Here.
我给你一些纸。
Let me give you some paper.
你给我看看你能为爷爷的公司画个logo。
And you show me what you can do about drawing a logo for Pop Pop's business.
如果你想继续，就按你的按钮。
If you wanna get that going, push your button.
在这里。按下按钮。
Right there. Push the button.
比尔?——嘿,杰里。嘿,玛姬。
Bill?- Hey, Jerry. Hey, Marge.
嗨。
Hi.
嘿，如果我们再这样，我要收你用微波炉的钱。
Hey, uh, if we're gonna do this again, I'm gonna need to charge you for using the microwave.
我们赌4万。
We are betting 40,000.
你们是毒贩吗?
You guys drug dealers?
不。我们是专业的彩票玩家。
No. We're professional lottery players.
我不认为这是一件事。
I don't think that's a thing.
这是现在。
It is now.
听着，虽然我很想知道你能不能在那后面站那么久而不摔断髋骨，但你不可能在打烊前买那么多票。
Listen, as much as I'd like to see if you can stand behind that thing for that long without breaking a hip, there's no way you can buy that many tickets before closing time.
你们能晚一点营业吗?
Can you stay open later?
哦，恐怕不行。
Oh, I'm afraid not.
我现在正经历婚姻创伤。
I'm undergoing some marital trauma at the moment.
哦。说实话，今晚要和我的朋友们喝酒庆祝。
Oh.Well, truth be told, tonight is a drinking celebration with my buddies.
诚然，我们会在外面做，在停车场，但是，我不能让顾客进来。
Now, admittedly we do it out there, in the parking lot, but, uh, I just can't have customers in here.
这是一个责任。
It's a liability.
嗯…如果我们不是顾客呢?
Well... What if we weren't customers?
我不知道你在说什么。
I have no idea what you're talking about.
如果我们是搭档呢?
What if we were partners?
比尔，我来给你介绍一下GS投资策略公司。
Bill, I'd like to introduce you to GS Investment Strategies.
我在。我能进来吗?
I'm in. Can I be in?
我是股东，如果你们愿意，我完全可以让你们加入。
So I'm a shareholder, and I could totally get you guys in if you want.
所以，这是一个WinFall，所以当数字…好吧，你是投资者……好吧，假设你有几百美元。
So, it's a WinFall, so when the numbers... Okay, you're an investor... Okay, let's say you've got several hundred dollars.
还有这些彩票号码。如果他们不打，你就赢了。
Then there is these lottery numbers. If they don't hit, you win.
你在吗?你有钱吗?
You in? You got any money?
我想我们讲完了。
I believe we are done.
嘿，我还有两个股东。
Hey, I got two more shareholders.
他们中肯定有人去抢他父母的房子，但他肯定在里面。
One of them's got to rob his parents' house real quick, but he's definitely in.
又多了500张票。
That's 500 more tickets.Yup.
好吧。
All right.
你要来一口吗?
You want a bong hit real quick?
我不知道那是什么。——玛姬?
I don't know what that is.- Marge?
不,谢谢,比尔。好吧。噢!
No thanks, Bill. All right. Ow!
我们的下一个数字是46…数24…今天最后一个数字是23。
Our next number is 46... Number 24... And our very last number for today is number 23.
所以，再来一次，这些数字是05、21、39、46、24、23……好了，开始。
So, one more time, those numbers are 05, 21, 39, 46, 24, 23... Okay, here we go.
不会再被烟烫伤了吧?是的。
No more cigarette burns, huh? Yeah.
嗯…我想我们可以喝点美味的汽车旅馆咖啡开始了。
Well... I guess we fire up some of that delicious motel coffee and get started.
或者可以等到明天早上。
Or it could wait till morning.
明天好吗?
Tomorrow?
哦。
Oh.
嗯。
Hmm.
彩票吗?
The lottery?
彩票中奖者的点击率很高。
Lottery winners get a lot of clicks.
我不做点击。我做新闻。
I don't do clicks. I do news.
你没看到这些空隔间吗?
Do you not see all these empty cubicles?
随便找点东西。
Just poke around for something.
给我找个头条放到重点报道的版面上。
Find me a headline that I can throw in the Spotlight section.
嗯。
Hmm.
这个床垫的好处是，我们都滚到中间去。
Oh, nice thing about this mattress is, we both roll to the center.
我想就算我试了也逃不出去。
I don't think I can get out if I tried.
我们还有时间。
Well, we have time.
什么?到底是什么?
What? What the heck?
嘿，嘿，好了，好了。
Hey, hey, all right, all right.
我走错房间了。我走错房间了。
Got the wrong room. Got the wrong room.
它来了!是什么?
It came in! What did?
彩票将商店售出的所有奖金的总数寄给顾客。
The lottery sends a tally of all the winnings sold by the store.
WinFall彩票赢得了8.2万美元。
WinFall tickets won $82,000.
你在你的店里卖了多少WinFall的票?
And how many WinFall tickets did you sell at your store?
就是你的，再加六个。是的!
Just yours, plus six more. Yes!
给我。但这些都没有胜出。
To me. But those didn't win.
我们增加了一倍。我们增加了一倍。
We doubled it. We doubled it.
我们增加了一倍!
We doubled it!
哇!
Whoo!
这是史蒂夫。
It's Steve.
嗨,史蒂夫。
Hey, Steve.
嘿,杰瑞。
Hey, Jerry.
我只是想看看我们进展如何。嗯，你知道，好奇。
I was just checking to see how we did. Um, you know, curious.
我会发出一份正式的股东报告。
I will be sending out an official shareholder report.
对，对，对，但你知道…他想知道。你觉得呢?
Yeah, yeah, right, right, but you know... He wants to know. What do you think?
我们把它翻倍了。
Well, we doubled it.
我们增加了一倍!
We doubled it!
嘘。
Shh.
这不可能是真的。我也不相信，但我在画画的时候做了模拟，结果是对的。
This can't be real. I didn't believe it either, but I've been running simulations during the drawings, and it's right.
如果你赌至少1万美元，赔率会向买家倾斜。
If you bet at least 10 grand, the odds tilt towards the buyer.
你能从你爸爸那里弄到钱吗?我没问他要什么。
Can you get money from your dad? I'm not asking him for shit.
为什么不呢?他的名字写在一栋建筑上。我想他能负担得起。
Why not? His name is on a building. I think he can afford it.
因为这是我的。
Because this is mine.
你有一万美元吗?不。
Do you have 10 grand? No.
我有一个宿舍。
I have a dorm.
也就是每人吃一片披萨。一片。谢谢你！
Okay, that is one slice of pizza per person. One slice. Thank you.
嘿，如果你捐了钱，就拿一块。
Hey, only take a piece if you contributed to the fund.
你们在哈佛学到的第一件事就是你们在这里是为了你们的未来。
The first thing you learn at Harvard is that you're here for your future.
对吧?
Right?
你学到的第二件事是……那都是扯淡。
Second thing you learn... Is that's all bullshit.
没有未来。
There is no future.
现在就等着你去拿。
There is just now waiting for you to take it.
我发现彩票有个缺陷。
I found a flaw in the lottery.
好吧?每次都能赢的方法因为没人知道我做了什么。
Okay? A way to beat the game every time because nobody at the lottery figured out what I did.
但只有在你能下大赌注的情况下，它才管用。
But it only works if you can bet big.
所以，告诉你的父母你要交新的实验费，或者需要书，或者得了性病。
So, tell your parents that you have new lab fees, or need books, or got an STD.
不惜一切代价，因为如果我们成功了，我们就是传奇!
Whatever it takes, because if we pull this off, then we are legends!
还有，我需要你们填300张彩票单，这样我们就不会重复下注了。
Also, I'm gonna need you all to fill out about 300 lottery slips, so we don't bet duplicates.
给你。那是你的。
Here you go. That's for you.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你什么都没填吗?
You're not filling any out?
不。我负责。
No. I'm in charge.
好吧，告诉我。你想重新装修吗?
Okay, talk to me. So you wanna renovate it?
是的。所有的股东都出资。
Yup. All the shareholders are chipping in.
我们要重新举办爵士音乐节。
We're bringing back the jazz festival.
最好的音乐是你在旅途中谱写的音乐。
The best music is the music you make up as you go along.
我只是很难过普林斯不在的时候我们没能拥有它。
Ah, I'm just sad we couldn't have had it when Prince was around.
他就不会来了，霍华德
He wouldn't have come, Howard.
我们永远不会知道。
We'll never know.
你们确定要这么花你们的钱吗?
You guys are sure this is what you wanna do with your money?
你不想投资吗?
You don't wanna invest it somewhere?
我们在某个地方投资。
We are investing it somewhere.
好吧。
All right.
我来帮你。好吧。
I'll give you a hand. All right.
道格，把它放在上面。好吧。
Doug, put it on top there.Yup. All right.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
哇。
Wow.
你为什么留着这些?
Why do you keep all these?
美国国税局。
The IRS.
当我们被审计时，我们需要一份所有遗失彩票的书面记录。
When we get audited, we'll need a paper trail of all the losing tickets we bought.
你觉得你会被审核吗?
Think you're gonna get audited?
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
耶稣。
Jesus.
你知道吗，你的团队雇我来修理露天剧场。六个月的工作。
You know, your group hired me to fix the amphitheater. Six-month job.
哦。你觉得怎么样?
Oh. How about that?
是啊，怎么样?
Yeah, how about that?
那你可以考虑帮我一把。
Well, you may wanna consider chipping in on that.
什么?
What?
好吧，你有一份。
Well, you have a share.
你从一开始就做到了。
You did, from the start.
爸爸……
Dad...
你不用这么做的。
You didn't have to do that.
没有你我可不想数硬币。
Oh, I didn't wanna count nickels without you.
我跟你说，多蒂把书店办得很好。
I'm telling you, Dottie has done such a great job with this bookstore.
是的。里昂正在装修酒店。
Yeah. You know, Leon is renovating the hotel.
霍华德给了他一个协议，但他的佣金是他和雪莉可以随时使用热水浴缸。
Howard got him a deal on it, but his commission is that he and Shirley get to use the hot tub whenever they want.
里昂会后悔的。
Leon will regret that.
你不是在开玩笑。
You are not kidding.
你好,大家好。——哦,嘿!
Hello, hello, everybody.- Oh, hey!
好吧。好吧,去吧……来吧，坐下。
All right. Well, go ahead... Go on, sit on down.
嗯…嗯…嗯…听着，首先，我可以说我们做得很好。
Uh... Uh... Well... Look, first off, I can say that we're doing pretty darn well.
是的。
Yes.
是的。但你可能已经通过阅读你的股东报告知道了……我的打不开。
Yeah. But you probably already know that by reading your shareholder report... I can't get mine to open.
哦，你有Word吗?
Oh, do you have Word?
我想我有Windows。
I have Windows, I think.
我给你印一份，雪莉。
I'll print you one, Shirley.
噢,谢谢你。
Oh, thank you.
Anyhoo……你可能已经想到了，我们要把大部分资金用于赌博。
Anyhoo... As you might have imagined it, we're gonna use the majority of our capital for betting.
是的。
Yeah.
但你可以获得一些红利。
But there are dividends that you can access.
正确的。所以，我知道很多人都想看到爵士音乐节回归。
Right. So, I know a lot of people would like to see the jazz festival come back.
而且，老弗兰克肯定会用一辆他不会掉下去的邮车。
And, Old Frank can sure use a mail truck he doesn't fall out of.
那么，现在来说说利润比率。我们……是的,拉杰?这里没有吃的吗?
Uh, so, now on to the profit ratios. We... Yes, Raj? Is there not food at this thing?
不。不。这是股东大会。这不是派对。
No. No. This is a shareholder meeting. It's not a party.
那你为什么在我们吃东西的时候吃?
Then why did you have it at - 00, when we all eat?
好吧，你们都可以去吃饭，但是…不，那你就不会知道那些数字了。
Well, you're welcome to all go to the diner, but... No, then you're not gonna learn about the numbers.
那么，下一步怎么办?
So, what's the next play?
312000张门票。
312,000 tickets.
这是600000美元。-是的。
That's $600,000.- Yeah.
我们在一场赌局下了50万?
We're betting half a million in one play?
钱是最容易的部分。
Oh, the money is the easy part.
是吗?是的。
Is it? Yeah.
四天的赌博，两台机器，一天12个小时。
It'll take four days of betting, two machines, 12 hours a day.
那你为什么不按正常金额下注呢?
Then why don't you just bet the normal amount?
数学。
Math.
这是牛顿定律。
It's Newton's law.
如果你推什么东西，它就会推回来。
If you push against something, it's gonna push back.
我们发现了一个缺陷。
And we discovered a flaw.
但是通过使用它，我们引入了一个变量来改变它。
But by using it, we've introduced a variable that changes it.
我们也不知道这场比赛会持续多久。
And we don't know how long this game is gonna last.
那我们就得趁现在尽可能多赚钱。
Then we need to make as much money as we can, while we can.
让节日开始吧，在它推迟之前完成重建。
Get the festival going, and finish rebuilding before it pushes back.
嗯。
Mmm-hmm.
我从彩票公司订购了第二台机器，但他们说每个地方只能买一台，所以我想，“如果我有第二家店呢?”
I ordered a second machine from the lottery, but they said you're only allowed one per location, so I was like, "Well, what if I have a second store?"
他们会问:“地址是什么?”我当时想:“哦哦。这是我的错误。”
They're like, "What's the address?" I was like, "Uh-oh. There's my mistake."
这就是我的朋友Darryl发挥作用的地方。
And that's where my buddy, Darryl, comes in.
我们会多给他一份，但给你。
And, uh, we're gonna give him an extra share, but here you are.
你可以一天24小时打印，外加无限的馅饼。
You can print out 24 hours a day, plus unlimited pie.
看看这个。
Look at this.
这是什么?
What's this?
从我在总检察长办公室的线人那里得到的。
From my source at the AG's office.
现在，彩票公司必须每年五次，公开那些索赔超过5万美元的玩家。
Now, the lottery has to disclose players who claim more than 50 grand, five times a year.
有时候赢家只是幌子，帮欠孩子抚养费的人，或者有搜查令的人兑现票，但看看这家伙。每三周大赢一次。
Sometimes the winners are fronts, you know, cashing tickets for people who owe child support, or have a warrant, but look at this guy. Wins big every three weeks.
住在密歇根。一个退休的工厂工人。
Lives in Michigan. A retired factory worker.
没有犯罪记录。
No criminal record.
他赢了这么多?是的。
He's won this much? Yeah.
谁每个月开10个小时的车去不同的州买彩票?
Who drives 10 hours every month to play the lottery in a different state?
这说不通啊对
Yeah, that doesn't make any sense.Right.
失败者!
Loser!
那个女人刚抢了你的东西吗?
Did that woman just rob you?
这是我的妻子。
That's my wife.
哇。
Wow.
嗯，她看起来很精神。
Well, she certainly seems spirited.
是啊，她是个好斗的人。
Yeah, she's a spitfire.
不，她只是因为我提出离婚而生气，她觉得我根本负担不起。
No, she's just pissed off 'cause I filed for divorce, and she didn't ever think I'd be able to afford it.
嗯。
Huh.
看来钱花得很值。
Looks like money well spent.Yeah.
自从史蒂利·丹停止巡演之后就没什么魔力了。
Kind of lost the magic ever since Steely Dan stopped touring.
你知道的…我需要找一个像你这样的人。
You know... I need to find someone like you.
只有年轻。是的，一开始很好。
Only younger. Yeah, that started off great.
不，我是说，你懂的，就是一个还能生育的人。
No, I mean, you know, just someone that's still fertile.
他们的子宫可以孕育婴儿。
And their womb can have babies.
你不擅长这个。
You're not good at this.
哦，我真的没有。你能帮我吗?
Oh, I'm really not. Can you help me?
我妈妈以前常说，“亲几只青蛙，然后当你找到你的王子，”你会发现青蛙更好，因为它们能让你笑。“
Well, my mother used to say, "Kiss a few frogs, then when you find your prince, "you'll realize that the frogs are better, 'cause they make you laugh."
嘲笑你算吗?
Does laughing at you count?
比尔，你需要一只新的青蛙。
Bill, you need a new frog.
我需要一只新的青蛙。
I need a new frog.
50000美元。
$50,000.
欢迎来到现在，贱人们。
Welcome to the now, bitches.
我们会赚很多钱，但这需要时间，汗水和激情，好吗?
We are going to make a shitload of money, but it's going to take time, and sweat, and passion, okay?
每个人都要填两叠单子。
So, everybody fill out two stacks of slips.
我们需要在未来三周内引进两万五千人。
We need to get 25,000 in in the next three weeks.
错了什么吗?
Something wrong?
另一组。
There's another group.
什么?
What?
支付本应更高。
The payout should have been bigger.
唯一说得通的是又有一群人吃了大麻，所以我查了每家店的销售情况。
The only thing that makes sense is another group eating into the pot, so I checked sales at every store.
这是公共信息?不，我黑进了州彩票。
That's public information? No, I hacked the state lottery.
好了。
Nice.
等待。这是我的笔记本。
Wait. That's my laptop.
是的。你应该在这之后销毁硬盘。
Yeah. You should destroy your hard drive after this.
Dude.Whatever。它工作。
Dude.Whatever. It worked.
看看桑德兰的奖金，只有两个地方。
Look at the winnings in Sunderland, from only two locations.
两个位置。他们必须买一个星期的票才能得到这样的数字。
Two locations. They'd have to buy tickets for a week to get those kind of numbers.
他们现在就在那里。
They're there right now.
嘿。我今晚很早就做完了。
Hey. I finished early tonight.
什么事那么匆忙?
What's the rush?
哦……你不会以为我会忘记我们的纪念日吧?
Oh... You didn't think I'd forget our anniversary, did you?
你刚从冷藏箱里拿出来的。嗯,是的。
Oh, you just got that out of the cooler. Well, yeah.
但我今早把它藏在哟呼后面了这样就没人能拿到它了。
But I hid it behind the Yoo-hoo this morning so that nobody would get it.
哇!
Whoo!
哇。
Wow.
你知道这样做很好。
You know it's good when it does that.
美丽的中国塑料。
Beautiful plastic china.
给你。
Here you go.
敬46年。
Here's to 46 more years.
欢呼。
Cheers.
哦。
Ooh.
我想我还欠你一个舞会之夜。
I think I still owe you a prom night.
我16岁的时候还容易些。
This was easier when I was 16.
你现在更漂亮了。
You're even more beautiful now.
这是过时的香槟话。
That's the out-of-date champagne talking.
是啊，他真不该卖这个。
Yeah, he really shouldn't be selling that.
哦。嗯。
Oh. Mmm.
没有老师把我们分开。
No teacher to pull us apart.
你们是另一组吗?
You guys are the other group?
哦,男人。我们以为会是犯罪集团之类的。唷。
Oh, man. We thought it was gonna be, like, a crime syndicate or something. Phew.
我不知道你在说什么。
I don't know what you're talking about.
抱歉，我们太没礼貌了。我是泰勒，这是埃里克。
Sorry, we are being super rude. I'm Tyler, this is Eric.
我们在哈佛开了一家博彩俱乐部。
We run a betting club at Harvard.
我们叫Random Industries，这也是我的滑板品牌的名字。
We're called Random Industries, which is also the name of my skateboard brand.
我就知道会有别人的。
Well, I figured there'd be somebody else.
我也是，但我没想到会这样。看看你们。这就像。
Me, too, but I mean, I didn't expect this. Look at you guys. It's like Up.
你想喝杯香槟吗?
Would you like a glass of champagne?
不，我只喝野格和红牛。但是谢谢你。
No, I only drink Jager and Red Bull. But thank you.
好吧，至少你永远不用担心变成我们这个年纪了。
Oh, well, at least you'll never have to worry about being our age.
听着，我们同时玩只会伤害彼此，所以我有个更好的提议。
Look, we're really only hurting each other by playing at the same time, so here's a better offer.
你加入我的小组，把你的钱加到我们的罐子里，我们来处理所有的赌注。
You join my group, add your capital to our pot, and we'll handle all the betting.
嗯，我不知道。
Well, I don't know.
我们喜欢做自己的事。
We kind of like to do our own thing.
什么?
What?
你什么都不用做就能得到报酬。
You'll get a cut without having to do anything.
我有一群赌徒。你甚至不用离开你的摇椅。
I have an army of bettors. You won't even have to leave your rocking chairs.
我们很好。
We're good.
这是为了赚钱。你喜欢钱，对吧?
This is about making money. You like money, right?
不像我喜欢其他东西那么喜欢。
Well, not as much as I like other things.
哦,我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
如果你们不介意的话，今天是我们的结婚纪念日。
Uh, now, look, if you two don't mind, this is our anniversary.
你破坏了我们酒店的气氛。
And you are killing the ambience of our liquor store.
欢迎你在路上喝一杯红牛。
You're welcome to take a Red Bull for the road.
或者一盒果汁。
Or maybe a juice box.
你数学很好。
You're good at math.
耶!
Yay!
我相信这对农场很有帮助，但在哈佛，我们学到了一种叫做二项分布的东西。
I'm sure that helps out on the farm, but at Harvard, we learn a little something called binomial distribution.
查一下。
Look it up.
然后你就会明白为什么你自己填单子的几率会更高。
Then you'll see why your odds are better when you fill out your own slips.
不客气
You're welcome.
二项分布只考虑两个因素。
Binomial distribution only considers two factors.
不是第三个，那是人为失误，也不是第四个，那是你填票的时间。
Not a third, which is human error, or a fourth, which is the time it takes for you to fill in the tickets.
你每赢10万就能赚32块。
You gain a whooping 32 bucks for every $100,000 you win.
不客气
You're welcome.
严重吗?闭嘴!
Seriously? Shut up!
什么?
What?
我想没有傻孩子就不叫毕业舞会了。
I guess it wouldn't be a prom without dumb teenagers.
这让我想起了我们上次讲到的地方。
That reminds me of where we left off.
那房子归我了?
So I get the house?
是的。你会得到一切。
Yes. You get everything.
比尔只想保住他在GS战略公司的份额。
Bill just wants to keep his share of GS Strategies.
无论什么。我得到了房子。
Whatever. I got the house.
祝你好运，坎迪斯。
Well, good luck to you, Candace.
你知道吗，我们在那里度过了几年美好的时光然后一切都变糟了。
You know, we had a few good years there before it all turned to shit.
我希望你能找到你的青蛙。
And I hope you find your frog.
啊哈。
Uh-huh.
嘿，什么是GS什么的?
Hey, what is GS whatever?
哦,是的。我是这个小公司的一份子。
Oh, yeah. That's a little company I'm a part of.
我们每个月都中彩票。
Uh, we win the lottery every month.
在见到你。
See you around.
我想让冰淇淋店重新开张。
I'd love to re-open the ice cream shop.
现在你可以以每年1.19美元的价格出租了。
Well, now you can lease it for $1.19 a year.
市区基金会支付剩下的。
And the Downtown fund will cover the rest.
1.19美元吗?嗯。
$1.19?Mmm-hmm.
哦，是一欧元。这是一个复杂的故事。
Oh, it's a euro. It's a complicated story.
杰瑞可以解释给你听。
Jerry can explain it to you.
男孩,男孩。
Boy, oh, boy.
我刚买了一辆克尔维特。是的，我看得出来。
I just bought a Corvette. Yeah, I can see that.
你想下星期去骑一骑吗?我要坐游轮去我的家乡。
You want to take it for a ride next week? I'm going on a cruise to Me-hi-co.
哦，不，我想我不能说这个。
Oh, no, I don't think I can get into it.
好吧，老头，随你便。
All right, old man, suit yourself.
另一组。
There's another group.
No.Yep。
No.Yep.
一些哈佛的孩子发现了这一点。
Some kids from Harvard figured it out.
嗯,这很糟糕。
Well, that sucks.
我们应该没事的。
We should be okay.
我们还是赢了足够的钱让人们重建爵士音乐节继续下去。
We're still winning enough for people to rebuild and get the jazz fest going.
我们只需要坚持下去。
We just have to stay in the game.
我们将。你说得倒轻巧。
And we will. Well, that's easy for you to say.
你又不是连续5天站在机器前。
You're not standing at a machine for five days straight.
我说过我要换班的。
I said I would take a shift.
不,不。没关系。
No, no. That's okay.
是啊，因为你们喜欢，对吧?
Yeah, because you guys like it, right?
是的,我们做的。是的,你做的事情。是的,你做的事情。
Yeah, we do. Yeah, you do. Yeah, you do.
真高兴你今天放假了。
So glad you got the day off.
我好像不知道。——哦,哦……你们这几周是怎么做到的?
Well, it doesn't feel like I did.- Oh, oh... How did you guys do this for weeks?
因为这是一场冒险。
Because it's an adventure.
不，这不是冒险。
Oh, no, this is not an adventure.
而是在满是妓女和毒贩的汽车旅馆里被纸割伤。
It's getting paper cuts in a motel filled with prostitutes and drug dealers.
哦。
Oh.
道恩，你没必要这么做。
Well, Dawn, you don't have to do it.
哦，不，不，我想。我做的事。
Oh, no, no, I want to. I do.
我是说，我从来没有机会和你们在一起，而且，你知道…感觉被困在一家恶心的酒店里，用丢失的票装满箱子只是我永远不会忘记的记忆。
I mean, I never get to spend time with you guys, and, you know... Feeling trapped in a gross hotel, filling bins with losing tickets is just a memory I will never ever forget.
哦。这是一个赢家。
Oops. This one's a winner.
哦，你错过了。我完成了。我完成了。
Oh, you missed it.Okay. I'm done. I'm done.
你什么时候能把所有的赢家都交上来?
Hey, when's the part where you get to turn in all the winners?
因为我会这么做的。嗯，那很有趣。
Because I will do that. Well, that is fun.
我们得再检查一下所有的…旅馆里有酒吧吗?
We're gonna have to double check all the... Is there a bar at this motel?
Grazio先生吗?
Mr. Grazio?
玛雅可要注意了。波士顿环球报。
Maya Jordon. Boston Globe.
我有一些关于《WinFall》游戏的问题。
I had some questions about the WinFall game.
梅兰妮·霍金斯负责我们的宣传。
Well, Melanie Hawkins handles our publicity.
但这项运动为该州带来了巨大的成功。
But the game has been a huge success for the state.
不仅仅是为了国家。
Not just for the state.
你知道密歇根有个玩家每个月都能赢几百万吗?
Are you aware there's a player in Michigan winning millions every month?
我们为学校筹集了很多钱，但没人写这方面的文章。
We raise a lot of money for schools, but nobody does an article about that.
某个退休的人走运了，就派了个重点报道的记者来?
Some retiree gets lucky and they send a Spotlight reporter?
我没说他退休了。
I didn't say he was a retiree.
是啊，你知道的，这是彩票。
Yeah, well, you know, it's a lottery.
人赢。所以，不能称之为新闻。
People win. So, wouldn't call it news.
我有个会。
I have a meeting.
谢谢您的宝贵时间。
Thanks for your time.
早上,莱昂。——早上,杰里。
Morning, Leon.- Morning, Jerry.
给你做了一口新鲜的法式烤肉。——哦。
Made you a fresh pot. French roast.- Oh.
哇。你得到的。
Wow. You're getting fancy.
嘿,杰瑞。
Hey, Jerry.
他们说我能在这里找到你。
They said I'd find you here.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
不会太久的。
This won't take long.
我们不加入你的小组。
We're not joining your group.
我不希望你这样。
I don't want you to.
我不需要你的资金了。
I don't really need your capital anymore.
我只需要你退出游戏。
I just need you out of the game.
所以,你是。什么?
So, you're out. What?
你看，你不像计算数字那样擅长计算人。
See, you're not really as good at calculating people as you are numbers.
所以你还没算过像我这样的人为了获胜会怎么做。
So you haven't really run the math on what somebody like me would do to win.
你会怎么做?
And what would you do?
组建一支由你所见过的最聪明的孩子组成的军队来对抗你和所有和你一起玩的人。
Set an army of the smartest kids you've ever met against you and everyone you play with.
我们黑进了州彩票公司想知道你在哪里下注。
We hacked into the state lottery to find where you were betting.
你觉得我们不能黑进你的账户吗?
You don't think that we can hack into your accounts?
你的信用?你的身份吗?
Your credit? Your identity?
这并不难。我的意思是……大多数人认为防火墙是他们烟囱里的东西，所以…你为什么要这么做?
It won't be hard. I mean... Most of them think a firewall is something in their chimney, so... Why are you doing this?
这只是数学。任何个人。
It's just math. Nothing personal.
听着，你干得不错。
Look, you had a good run.
你为梅贝瑞赚了些钱。
You made some cash for Mayberry.
但这是结束了。
But it's over.
享受你的黄金岁月。
Enjoy your golden years.
嘿，你觉得我们需要几天时间?
Hey, so how many days do you think we'll need?
一个也没有。
None.
我们出局了。
We're out of the game.
杰里!
Jerry!
哦……嗯…好吧。呃。
Oh... Uh... Okay. Uh.
哦,男孩。嗯,嗯…我很遗憾地告诉大家，由于游戏中出现了一些新的变量……嗯…我们不能再玩了。
Oh, boy. Well, uh... I'm sad to report that, due to some new variables in the game... Um... We're going to have to stop playing.
嗯…我很抱歉。
Um... I am sorry.
你真的要让一个大学里的小聪明把这一切都夺走吗?
So, you're really going to let some college smart ass take all this away from you?
他做某事的可能性大于好处。这与数学无关。这是关于人类的。
The odds that he might do something outweigh the benefits... It's not about the math. It's about being human.
你知道，爸爸，我…我看着你一生中很多时候都被人忽视被人摆布。
You know, Dad, I... I've watched you spend so much of your life just being overlooked and pushed around.
没人知道你能做什么。
Nobody knew what you could do.
没有人关心。
Nobody cared.
然后你终于抓住了机会，把我们都带来了。
And then you finally took your shot, and you brought us all with you.
你知道你做了什么吗?你让我们的小镇显得很大。
You know what you did? You made our little town feel big.
所以它们都在里面。
That's why they're all in there.
所以我才会在那里。
That's why I was in there.
他会没事的。
He'll be okay.
你知道我为什么不喜欢钓鱼吗?
You know why I don't like to fish?
不。
No.
我上次去的时候，带着他。
The last time that I went, I took him with me.
那时他16、17岁。
He was 16, 17.
然后我开始计算漂浮物移动的速度这样我就能算出水流的速度。
And I started calculating how fast the bobber was moving so I can figure out the speed of the current.
然后我听到他问我:“爸爸，你觉得怎么样?”
And then I hear him ask me, "What do you think, Dad?"
就在那一刻，我意识到他说的是一个他喜欢的女孩。
And it was at that moment that I realized he was talking about a girl that he liked.
和…哦。
And... Oh.
我完全不知道。
I had no idea.
你知道,这是……这从来不是一种天赋。这是个骗局。
You know, it's... It's never been a gift. It's been a trick.
你的大脑告诉你，你看到了别人看不到的东西，但最终，你看到的只是更少。
Your brain tells you that you see what other's don't, but in the end, you're just seeing less.
嗯…我想今晚我要步行回家。
Uh... I think I'll walk home tonight.
好了，伙计们，这可是个大场面。现在是我们大家的事了，所以要珍惜。
All right, guys, it's gonna be a big one. It's all of us now, so make it count.
走,走,走。
Go, go, go.
这周末滚吧。
Roll down's this weekend.
嗯。我知道。
Mmm-hmm. I know.
我只是想做正确的事。
I'm just trying to do the right thing.
哦，你总是这样。我喜欢你这一点。
Oh, you always do. I love that about you.
所以镇上的人都相信你会去冒险。
And that's why everyone in town trusts you to take a chance.
我从没见过你做过的一件事就是在找到解决办法之前就放弃。
The one thing I have never seen you do is give up on a problem before you find a solution.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
你计算了泰勒的威胁，和游戏的价值，但二项分布没有考虑第三个因素。
Well, you've calculated Tyler's threat, and the value of the game, but binomial distribution doesn't consider the third factor.
只要你我拥有彼此，我们就不怕犯傻。
That as long as you and I have each other, we are not afraid to be stupid.
你真是疯了。
You're bat shit crazy.
哦,有史蒂夫。
Oh, there's Steve.
我们要去马萨诸塞州。
We're heading to Massachusetts.
哈哈!我看到你!抓住他们，孩子!
Ha-ha! I see you! Go get 'em, boy!
哇!好，我们开始吧!玛姬!给我五个。
Whoa! Yeah, let's do this! Marge! Give me five.
杰里!你是一个疯子。英镑我。
Jerry! You're a madman. Pound me.
我还以为没有分手会更有意思呢。
I thought it was supposed to be more without the split.
你查过其他索赔吗?是的。有一个。
Did you check for other claims? Yes. There was one.
在哪里?桑德兰。
Where? Sunderland.
狗屎!
Shit!
他说你在虚张声势，好吗?除了接受，我们别无他法。
He called your bluff, okay? There's nothing we can do but accept it.
如果有一个滚下，他就会玩。
If there's a roll down, he's going to play.
除非我们创建向下滚动。什么?
Unless we create the roll down. What?
一卷要好几周，对吧?
It takes weeks for a roll down, right?
我的意思是，WinFall每天赚10万，当它达到200万时，我们知道要下注了，所有人都开始下注，本杰明·巴顿就上了他的车。
I mean, WinFall takes in 100 grand a day, and then when it hits two million, we know a roll down is coming in, and everybody starts betting, and Benjamin Button gets in his truck.
但如果我们在没人预料到的时候制造了一个滚下，我们就把它全拿走。
But if we create a roll down when nobody expects it, we take it all.
我们把其他玩家排挤出去。
We squeeze the other players out.
我们用我们的黑客追踪大麻，等它涨到一百万再开奖，然后我们在一天内下注一百万。我是说，我们拥有这个游戏。
We use our hack to track the pot, we wait for it to hit a million before a drawing, and then we bet a million in one day. I mean, we own the game.
那我们从哪弄到一百万?
And where do we get $1 million?
正如您从我们的回报中看到的，它是有效的。
As you can see by our returns, it works.
有了更多的资本，我们就能控制局面。
And with more capital, we can control the game.
你爸爸也参与了吗?
Is your dad in on this?
不。他……嗯…认为你要去上大学?
No. He... Um... Thinks you're going to college?
他以为我和他一样，在学习做律师。
He thinks I'm studying to be a lawyer, like him.
但据我所知，我父亲从没一夜赚过一百万。
But last time I checked, my father never made $1 million in a night.
我们有14个小时来搞定。
We have 14 hours to pull this off.
到达目的地，打印好所有的票后再离开。
Get to your location and don't leave until you print all your tickets.
有些地方可能会推迟打印一整天，但不要让他们这么做。
Some locations might push back on printing all day, but do not let them.
他们为我们工作。
They work for us.
让我们骑。
Let's ride.
是的!——哇!
Yes!- Whoo!
是的。
Yeah.
嘿。如果有人赢了头奖而我们输了100万怎么办?
Hey. What happens if somebody wins the jackpot and we lose $1 million?
除了因为我花光了所有学费而辍学吗?
Beyond dropping out of school because I blew my entire tuition?
我觉得其中一个投资人可能会杀了我。
I think one of those investors might actually kill me.
哦。
Ooh.
你对吧?-好的，我知道了。
You all right?- Yeah, I got it.
哦。好吧。
Oh. Okay.
我拿到钥匙了。
I got the key.
到底是什么?
What the heck?
哦。
Oh.
嘿!
Hey!
我们错过了!
We missed it!
怎么，有人把六个号码都打中了吗?
What, someone actually hit all six numbers?
不。不。它滚下来。
No. No. It rolled down.
不,那是不可能的。这只是第二周。
No, that's impossible. It's only the second week.
它从不在三点前滚下来。
It never rolls down before three.
它昨晚滚下来了，我们错过了。
It rolled down last night, and we missed it.
哈佛大学的小组是自己触发的。
The Harvard group triggered it on their own.
他们怎么知道该赌多少钱?
How would they know how much to bet?
彩票没有公布金额…嗯,他们知道。
The lottery doesn't post the amount... Well, they knew.
杰里?
Jerry?
杰瑞，你要去哪儿?
Where are you going, Jerry?
杰里!
Jerry!
都上新闻了。彩票甚至没有预见到它的到来。
It's on the freakin' news. The lottery didn't even see it coming.
这太史诗了。
This is so epic.
嘿,杰瑞。
Hey, Jerry.
怎么，你是开着拖拉机过来跟我大吼大叫的吗?
What, did you come ridin' in on your tractor to come give me a whoopin'?
相信我，我也想。
Believe me, I wanted to.
我内心的一部分仍然如此。
Part of me still does.
但是开了这么长时间的车来这里，大部分都消失了。
But then on the long drive here, well, most of that just, poof, went away.
我意识到我并不是真的生你的气。
And I realized that I wasn't really angry at you.
我很失望。
I'm disappointed.
你对我很失望?
Aw, you're disappointed in me?
不,不是你。你是无关紧要的。
No, not you. You're insignificant.
不，我很失望让你这样一个自私的孩子影响了我。嗯。
No, I was disappointed that I let a selfish kid like you get to me. Huh.
我数学一直很好，但我要花很长时间才能理解别人。
I was always good with math, but it took a long time for me to figure people out.
告诉我们，杰瑞，你发现了什么?
So, tell us, Jerry, what did you figure out?
解决方案不是数字。
That the solution isn't numbers.
你说我买彩票是因为我一无所有。
You told me that I was playing the lottery because I had nothing else.
但你不愿分享这壶是因为你没有别的了。
But the reason you won't share the pot is because you have nothing else.
你以为做屋里最聪明的人就够了吗。
You think being the smartest guy in the room is all that matters.
但事实证明，这个房间才是最重要的。
But it turns out it's this room that matters.
这些聪明的年轻人帮你致富。
All these bright, young people helping you get rich.
你是如何帮助他们的?
How are you helping them?
我猜你还没算出来吧?
Guess you haven't run the math out on that, huh?
无论如何……我的拖拉机跑。
Anyway... my tractor's running.
祝你万事如意。
I wish you all the best of luck.
什么?继续数吧。
What? Just get back to counting.
如果哈佛队能触发下滚，他们就能掌控比赛。
If the Harvard team can trigger a roll down, they run the game.
所以我们触发了自己的向下滚动。
So we trigger our own roll down.
是的，我们有足够的现金。
Yeah, we have enough cash.
No.Why吗?
No.Why?
因为这对普通球员不公平。
Because it's not fair to the regular players.
他是对的。我们不是这样的人。
He's right. It's not who we are.
但我们已经很接近了。
But we're so close.
我是说，市中心又回来了，爵士音乐节就要来了。
I mean, downtown is back, the jazz fest is coming.
如果我们一直赢，我们就可以雇人去那里打球。
If we keep winning, we could actually hire somebody to play there.
你应该找钢铁丹。
You should get Steely Dan.
这主意太棒了。我们应该找钢铁丹。
That is an amazing idea. We should get Steely Dan.
我们不玩就赢不了。
We can't win if we can't play.
这太糟糕了。
Well, this just sucks.
彩票不能阻止我们，一群大学生却能?
The lottery isn't stopping us, but a bunch of college kids are?
嗯，说得好。是什么?我不是在说什么。
Huh, that's a good point. What is? I wasn't making a point.
为什么彩票没有阻止他们?
Why isn't the lottery stopping them?
那是因为他们不在乎。
It's because they don't care.
哦。
Oh.
这可能是我们的答案。
That could be our answer.
很高兴见到我们的忠实玩家，赛尔比先生和夫人。
Always happy to meet with our loyal players, Mr. and Mrs. Selbee.
哦,请。“杰里和马姬”就可以了。
Oh, please. "Jerry and Marge" is fine.
我们能为您做些什么?
What can we help you with?
事情是这样的。
So here's the thing.
几年前，州彩票一直在赔钱，几乎没有人中头奖，所以超级百万吃掉了你的午餐。
The state lottery was losing money a few years ago, and hardly anybody was winning the jackpot, so Mega Millions ate your lunch.
然后随着WinFall的到来，一切都改变了。
Then along comes WinFall, and all that changes.
你们赚了几百万，然后才意识到数学上的缺陷。
You folks made millions, before you realized there was a flaw in the math.
一开始你可能会惊慌失措，因为你知道一旦所有人看到它，游戏就会崩溃。
You probably panicked at first, because you knew that once everybody saw it, that the game would collapse.
只是他们没有看到。
Except they didn't see it.
只有我和几个哈佛的孩子。
Only me and a few kids from Harvard.
这意味着我们在游戏中投入了数百万美元，让你的利润飙升。
Which meant that we were pushing millions into the game, and, boy, sent your profits through the roof.
所以，突然之间，你的错误变成了你的意外之财。
So, all of a sudden, your mistake became your windfall.
我给了他那句台词。
I gave him that line.
是啊，没错，而且很漂亮。
Yeah, she sure did, and it's a dandy.
你到底想要什么?
So, what exactly do you want?
透明度。
Transparency.
我们希望网站显示的大小，头奖。
We'd like the website to show the size of the jackpot.
这可以防止任何团体强行向下滚动。
That prevents any group from forcing a roll down.
对所有参赛选手都公平。
Makes it fair for anybody who plays.
我们想在桑德兰的酒屋买两台机器。
And we would like two machines at the Liquor Hut in Sunderland.
这样我们才能在一起。
So we can be together.
这是我们的黄金岁月。
These are our golden years.
我们会处理的。
We'll take care of it.
是啊，我们很快就会有新戏了。
Yeah, we'll be making another play soon.
听你这么说太好了。是的。说话很快。
That's great to hear. Yeah. Talk soon.
他想从律所引进其他合伙人。
He's wants to bring in other partners from the firm.
伙计，我们可能永远都不需要一份真正的工作。
Dude, we might not ever need a real job.
他们中了头奖。什么?
They posted the jackpot. What?
彩票改变了网站。你可以在网上追踪头奖。
The lottery changed the website. You can track the jackpot online.
我们不能再把它滚下来了。
We can't roll it down anymore.
大便。大便。
Shit. Shit.
好吧，我们来对付这家伙。
All right, let's break this guy.
他想要战争?我们会给他一个。
He wants a war? We'll give him one.
你想吃玉米片吗?哦,不。
You want some nachos? Uh, no.
是的，我要尝尝。
Yeah, I'll try some.
你知道，我很好。
You know, I'm good.
每个人都在哪里?我们应该打赌的。
Where is everyone? We're supposed to be betting.
老兄,这是结束了。没人想再这么做了。
Dude, it's over. Nobody wants to do it anymore.
什么?为什么?我们赢了。
What? Why? We're winning.
不。我们是混蛋。
No. We're assholes.
这对任何人都没用，除了你。
And that doesn't work for anybody but you.
很好。我自己来做。
Fine. I'll do it on my own.
这太疯狂了。
It's gonna be insane.
疯了。
Crazy.
我告诉过你我们应该…你买椒盐脆饼了吗?-是的。
I told you we should have... Did you get the pretzels?- Yeah.
这是给你的。谢谢你！
This just came for you. Thank you.
哦。最后。
Oh. Finally.
薪水吗?
Paycheck?
好像我会为此感到兴奋似的。
Like I'd get excited about that.
不。州彩票委员会。
No. State lottery commission.
他们不想跟我谈，但任何赢了6万以上的人都会被载入公共记录。
They don't want to talk to me, but anybody that wins above 60,000 is in the public record.
你只需要提交一个请求。
You just have to submit a request.
过去六个月的每一幅画我都画了。
Which I did, for every drawing in the last six months.
杰拉德·塞尔比，每三周。
Gerald Selbee, every three weeks.
嗯。
Mmm-hmm.
泰勒朗格弗德。
Tyler Langford.
相同的图纸。
Same drawings.
有另一个。
There's another one.
嗯。
Huh.
泰勒朗格弗德。泰勒朗格弗德。
Tyler Langford. Tyler Langford.
好的，泰勒·兰福德，我看到你了。
Okay, Tyler Langford, I see you.
这是我花过的最好的一欧元。
Best euro I've ever spent.
谢谢,拉吉。——谢谢。
Thanks, Raj.- Thank you.
好吧,女孩。
Okay, girl.
该死的!——哇!
Darn!- Whoa!
再试一次，亲爱的。
Try one more time, sweetheart.
像袋鼠一样。
Like a kangaroo.
嘿，你能给我一个一千万吗?是的。
Hey, would you hand me a 10 mil? Yeah.
10毫升。
Ten mil.
给你。谢谢你！
Here you go. Thank you.
你都不给自己买辆新卡车吗?
You won't even buy yourself a new truck?
不。这个作品。
Nah. This one works.
不是吗?
Does it?
不是一直都是这样。但我想这就是我喜欢它的原因。
Not all the time. But I think that's why I like it.
嗯。
Hmm.
你知道吗?
You know what?
我确实买了这个。
I did buy this.
我和你一起数镍币是因为我能理解。
I counted nickels with you because it was something I understood.
我不知道还有什么更好的方式和你共度时光。
I didn't know a better way to spend time with you.
我只知道我想这么做。
I just knew that I wanted to.
你知道是怎么回事吗?
You know how it works?
我假设你创造了自旋，这样它就有了第三个轴，这样风就可以抵消重力。
Well, I assume you create spin, which gives it a third axis, so that the wind can offset the gravity.
是的,就是这样。就像这样。
Yeah, that's it. Just like that.
想要验证这个理论吗?
Wanna test that theory?
好吧。
All right.
手指放在鞋带上。
Fingers on the laces.Yeah.
哦,好吧。不坏。
Oh, well. Not bad.
我会解决的。我知道你会的。
I'll work it out. I know you will.
哦,就是这样。——Selbee先生吗?
Oh, that's it.- Mr. Selbee?
玛雅可要注意了。波士顿环球报。
Maya Jordon. Boston Globe.
我想问你一些关于GS投资策略的问题。
I'd like to ask you some questions about GS Investment Strategies.
你和你妻子在酒店房间里数了11天的票?
So, you and your wife count tickets in a hotel room for 11 days?
是的。
Yup.
工作量太大了。
That's so much work.
嗯。
Mmm.
这看起来不像是工作。
It doesn't seem like work.
我一生都在工作。
I've worked all my life.
这是不同的。
This is different.
这是非常不同的。
This is very different.
你寄过去了吗?
You send it in yet?
他们帮助了整个小镇。
They helped their entire town.
问题不在于故事本身。
The flaw isn't the story.
这可不是什么吹捧的文章。
Well, this can't be a puff piece.
我需要一个头条新闻。
I need a headline.
啊。
Ah.
如果我们做得很好，我们就不需要这个游戏了。
Well, we do well on this one, we won't need the game anymore.
你知道吗，我在想，如果我们要为小镇建立一个基金，管理它，就得全职工作了。
You know, I was thinking, if we're going to have a fund for the town, managing it, it's gonna be a full-time job.
嗯…你觉得我们能在市中心弄间办公室吗，像史蒂夫的那样?
Well... Hey, you think we can get one of those offices downtown, like Steve's?
什么?
What?
我已经在他旁边买了一个了。
I already got us one right next to his.
你做了吗?是的!
You did? Yes!
事实上，他的克尔维特就停在我们的一个停车位上。
In fact, his Corvette is actually in one of our parking spots.
好吧，我们得处理一下。
Well, we'll have to take care of that.
什么?他们要把WinFall的机器搬出去。
What? They're moving out the WinFall machine.
嘿,嘿!嘿。嘿!
Hey, hey! Hey. Hey!
嘿。比尔!比尔,发生了什么事?
Hey. Bill! Bill, what happened?
彩票吊销了我们的执照。
The lottery suspended our license.
为什么?你没看到那篇文章吗?
Why? You didn't see the article?
哦。
Oh.
嘿,哥们。学校怎么样?哦,爸爸。
Hey, buddy. How's school? Uh, Dad.
你在这里做什么?你是著名的。
What are you doing here? You're famous.
伟大的举动,天才。
Great move, genius.
我们走吧。收拾好你的东西。你回家。
Let's go. Pack up your stuff. You're coming home.
现在。
Now.
大量投注的集团发现了游戏中的一个漏洞，并利用它获利数百万美元。
The high-volume betting groups discovered a flaw in the game and took advantage of it, to the tune of millions of dollars.
彩票官员对这一发现表示惊讶，并宣布他们将在今晚开奖后逐步取消这项比赛。
Lottery officials expressed their surprise at the discovery and announced they will phase out the game after tonight's drawing.
继续我们的下一个…最后一卷是今天。你本可以赢得最后的胜利。
Moving on to our next... The last roll down was today. You could've gotten your final win.
是的。但即使我们找到一个地方打赌，感觉也不会一样了。
Yes. But even if we found a place to bet, it wouldn't have felt the same.
对他来说，这不仅仅是一场游戏。
It was more than just a game to him.
他终于可以用他的天赋与人交流了。
He finally got to use his gift to connect to people.
杰里!
Jerry!
什么?
What?
股东们今晚要开会，我想知道你能不能过来一趟。
The shareholders are having a meeting tonight and were wondering if you could stop by.
他们是沮丧吗?
Are they upset?
如果我告诉你，你就不会来了。
If I told you that, you wouldn't come.
我试图在时事通讯上回答他们所有的问题。
I tried to answer all their questions in the newsletter.
我觉得他们不知道怎么打开通讯。
I don't think they know how to open the newsletter.
他们什么都不用担心。
Well, they don't have to worry about anything.
我们没有违反任何法律。
We didn't break any laws.
神圣的…这是爵士乐节?什么?
Holy... It's jazz fest? What?
杰里!玛姬!——嗯。
Jerry! Marge!- Huh.
是啊!
Yeah!
来吧!
Come on!
让我们这样做!
Let's do this!
是啊!好了,对吧?
Yeah! Okay, right?
周和玛姬!
Jer and Marge!
你是怎么……我们错过了最后的演出。
How did you... We missed the final play.
哦，不，我们没有。
Oh, no, we did not.
是啊，每个人都抢了一间店，爸爸。整个州。
Yeah, everybody took a store, Dad. All across the state.
我们有一辆公共汽车和一切。
We had a bus and everything.
什么?哦。
What? Oh.
你不用这么做的。
You didn't have to do that.
你这么做是为了我们。我们为什么不帮你呢?
You did it for us. Why wouldn't we do it for you?
别担心，我们把计数的部分留给你们了。
And don't worry, we left you two the counting part.
嘿,拉吉!
Hey, Raj!
我想帮忙，但我不会数数。
I would help, but, uh, I can't count.
是的,你可以。我可以计算。我只是不喜欢数。
Yes, you can. I can count. I just don't like to count.
这个小镇不只是报纸上的文章，杰瑞。是我们所有人。
This town isn't just a newspaper article, Jerry. It's all of us.
你在别人都做不到的时候让这个小镇起死回生，因为你不认为我们只是数字。
And you brought this town back from the dead when nobody else could, because you don't think we're just numbers.
不。不。
No. No.
你的家人。
You're family.
女士们先生们，掌声欢迎托丽·凯利!
Ladies and gentlemen, please put your hands together for Tori Kelly!
♬星星在你的头顶上闪烁♬晚风似乎在轻轻地说:“我爱你……”
♪ Stars shining bright Above you ♪ Night breezes seem To whisper "I love you..."
好吗?
Shall we?
这是爵士音乐节。
It is jazz fest.
♬鸟儿在枫树上歌唱♬做一个关于我的小梦♬说晚安然后吻我♬紧紧地抱着我告诉我你会想我当我孤独忧伤的时候就这样
♪ Birds singing in the Sycamore tree ♪ Dream a little dream of me ♪ Say nighty-night And kiss me ♪ Just hold me tight And tell me you'll miss me ♪ While I'm alone and blue As can be
♬在梦里有我♬星星在褪色但我在坚持，亲爱的……嗨,史蒂夫。嘿,罗达。
♪ Dream a little dream of me ♪ Stars fading But I linger on, dear... Hey, Steve. Hey, Rhoda.
你知道吗，我一直在为你策划"美食，祈祷，爱情"之旅。
Hey, you know, I've been working on that Eat, Pray, Love trip for you.
我得到了一些优惠。
I got some great rates.
哦。这是令人兴奋的。谢谢you.Yeah。
Ooh. That's exciting. Thank you.Yeah.
是的,当然。
Yeah, sure.
你想跳舞吗?
Um, do you want to dance?
嗯,是的。我是说，你有吗?
Um, yeah. I mean, do you?
是的。这就是我问的原因。
Yes. That's why I asked.
正确的。这是有道理的。
Right. That does make sense.Yeah.
好吧。
Okay.
♪但是在你的梦里不管它们是什么♪做一个关于我的小梦…你有多想去数那些票?
♪ But in your dreams Whatever they be ♪ Dream a little dream Of me... How badly do you want to go and just count all those tickets?
嗯。
Mmm.
我现在竭尽全力不去做这件事。
It's taking everything in me not to do it right now.
我会想念它的。是的,是的。
I'm going to miss it. Yeah, yeah.
我也是。
Me, too.
我真希望我们中了头奖。只有一次。
I kinda wish we'd won the jackpot. Just once.
我们还没开始，我就赢了头奖。
I won the jackpot before we ever started.
♪♪星星褪色但我还在，亲爱的♪依然渴望你的吻……杰里和玛姬解散了我们的赌博小组因为WinFall游戏被淘汰了。
♪ Stars fading But I linger on, dear ♪ Still craving your kiss... Jerry and Marge dissolved our betting group when the WinFall game was phased out.
他们用大部分的彩票奖金为埃瓦特镇开办了一项建筑贷款业务。
They used most of their lottery winnings to start a construction loan business for the town of Evart.
像他们的许多朋友和邻居一样，他们也供子女和孙辈上学。
Like many of their friends and neighbors, they also put their children and grandchildren through school.
我自己投资了一个非常豪华的男人窝。
I myself invested in a very luxurious man cave.
哇!啊!
Whoo! Ah!
杰里最终还是让步了，给自己买了一辆新卡车，但这辆车实际上用得很少，因为他认为这是一个更明智的购买。
Jerry did finally give in and buy himself a new truck, which was actually slightly used, because he calculated that was a smarter purchase.
他会知道的。
And he would know.
他的彩票计算总共赢得了2700万美元。
His lottery calculation won a grand total of $27 million.
好了，我们去数数。
Okay, let's go count.
♬做一个关于我的小梦
♪ Dream a little dream of me
他赚了多少钱?
He made how much?